The rebellion begins.
Harry Potter and the Order of the Phoenix is a
adventure, fantasy film directed by David Yates.
Returning for his fifth year at Hogwarts, Harry is stunned to find that his
warnings about the return of Lord Voldemort have been ignored.
Left with no choice, Harry takes matters into his own hands, training a small group
of motivated students to defend themselves against the Dark Arts.
Harry Potter, played by Daniel Radcliffe.
Ron Weasley, played by Rupert Grint.
Hermione Granger, played by Emma Watson.
Dolores Umbridge, played by Imelda Staunton.
Bellatrix Lestrange, played by Helena Bonham Carter.
Rubeus Hagrid, played by Robbie Coltrane.
Harry Potter and the Order of the Phoenix is a 2007 fantasy film directed
by David Yates from a screenplay by Michael Goldenberg.
It is based on the 2003 novel Harry Potter and the Order of the Phoenix by J.
It is the sequel to Harry Potter and the Goblet of Fire (2005) and
the fifth instalment in the Harry Potter film series.
The film stars Daniel Radcliffe as Harry Potter, alongside Rupert Grint and Emma Watson
as Harry's best friends Ron Weasley and Hermione Granger respectively.
Its story follows Harry's fifth year at Hogwarts School of Witchcraft and Wizardry
as the Ministry of Magic is in denial of Lord Voldemort's return.
Filming took place in England and Scotland for exterior locations and Leavesden Film Studios in Watford
for interior locations from February to November 2006, with a one-month break in June.
Post-production on the film continued for several
months afterwards to add in visual effects.
The film's budget was reportedly between £75 and 100 million ($150–200 million).
Harry Potter and the Order of the Phoenix was released in 2D cinemas and IMAX formats in the
United States on 11 July 2007 and in the United Kingdom on 12 July, by Warner Bros.
The film received generally positive reviews from critics and was nominated for many awards,
including the BAFTA Award for Best Production Design and Special Visual Effects.
With a worldwide five-day opening of $333 million and a total gross of $942 million, it was the
second-highest-grossing film of 2007, and was noted as a case of Hollywood accounting, as Warner Bros.
claimed that it lost $167 million despite the total gross.
A sequel, Harry Potter and the Half-Blood Prince, was released in 2009.
The film explores themes of witch, dying and death, court, magic, prophecy.
The tone is dark.